Hello and welcome to Real Easy English we're back with another conversation in Ey English to help with your learning I'm Bacca and I'm Neil don't forget there is a video
Version of this podcast on our website it's got subtitles on it to help you learn flats atbbclearningenglish.com. .
Today Neil we're talking about climate change you might have heard this term climate change but what does it mean So it's an interesting topic isnn't
It important one, climate change is the change in weather over a long period of time and when we talk about climate change now we're
Talking mainly about the world getting hotter yes, how is climate change affecting where you live?
Well, Becca, I remember a few years ago in July, I think the temperature in the UK hit40 degrees on one day.
And that is something I have never experienced in my life40 degrees in the UK is crazy and it was hot recently here as well, wasn't it Yeah, it was.
We don't usually have30 degree days in May, but it reached30 degrees and it was so hot and if you turn on the news,
You always hear stories these days about the hottest this, the wettest this, the windt this, so we hear a lot about extreme weather.
Yeah, and experts say that this could be because of greenhouse gases, greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide, for example, they stay in the Earth's atmosphere and they trap the sun's heat.
In the atmosphere, meaning that the earth gets hotter and hotter Yeah, and so one thing that scientists say is that we should burn fewer fossil fuels.
Now fossil fuels are things like oil and gas that come from the earth and when you burn them, they create carbon dioxide CO2.
But it's not all bad news, Neil, a lot of people are using renewable energy, so renewable energy is energy that comes from.
Things like the wind or from the sun that aren't likely to run out energy conservation is also really important becca, so for example, that means not using too much energy.
Especially if you don't really need to, so for example, not having your heating turned up too high.
Maybe using public transport instead of driving so that you don't use too much fuel and we can also talk about water conservation and that means
Not using too much water.
Okay, so like when I turn the tap off when I brush my teeth, exactly.
So let's recap the vocabulary that we heard in this episode starting with fossil fuels, fossil fuels are things like oil, gas and coal, which we burn to get energy.
And when we burn them, they release carbon into the atmosphere carbon dioxide is one of the gases that we call greenhouse gases.
Now greenhouse gases are those gases that keep the heat inside the Earth's atmosphere we also heard energy conservation and that means using Less.
Energy conservation means protecting something, so you can also conserve.
W and that means not using too much water if you don't have to and lastly, renewable energy and this is the energy that we can make from things like the wind,
The sun or the movement of water That's it for this episode of real easy English but we have a worksheet which you can download for our website so you can test'slening.
And we'll be back next week with another conversation in real easy.
English, but for now goodbye goodbye.